Initially the wins were people saying oh
I'm using dev mate and then there was
equally some people that were suffering
and that was when we start to experiment
with things like unsupervised agents.
>> You've been interacting with an LM and
it has to have the context of what
you're doing. So what the ripper 5 model
does it tells [music] the LLM that ask
me questions analyze the codebase of
where you're at.
>> Treat your AI like a basic junior
engineer. If you don't give him the full
requirements of the task he's not going
to be able to figure it out. When you
have hundreds of metrics written in
[music] C, you break it down into
basically a bunch of similar tasks that
can be verified in a standardized way.
One of the things that are really nice
about communities is that everyone, you
know, you get so many different people
at different levels of their experience
and adoption. And and this kind of like
leans into one thing that you mentioned
as well, which is like these maturity
models. I guess there's maturity in
terms of how an individual is using it
as well as a team. Talk us through the
maturity models and why they're
important.
>> So the the thing about the maturity
model, I intended it to be used for a
team, but there is a a dimension on
there which is about individual
productivity as well. So you can reflect
on your own kind of performance and ways
that you're getting value from it. Um
the benefit of it being a team based
thing is that it opens up the
conversation within your team. Yes. And
so you can generate uh ideas and have
action plans that are specific to you
because every team's going to have
slightly different context or different
levels of ability and different
interests. So that's great. Um we tried
to model it in a way that was going to
be fairly agnostic of the tooling and
and be durable because again the value I
think is that you can have these models
and you can repeat the the assessments
time after time and see how you're
progressing. Um and we do subtly tweak
it every now and again but um generally
it's kept fairly consistent and then
yeah like say the teams run these
assessment workshops and they can have
the discussion and that's that's where
the real value lies.
>> Yeah. Yeah. Let's talk about value and
wins. What were the what were the big
wins that you saw and and how did you
share that across the community? So
initially the wins were people saying
I'm using DevMate which is part of our
tool set in VS Code that we work with
dayto-day and I'm finding ways to use
this to like understand the code base
better or or what have you and there
were some early examples of people just
sort of going for a big problem and and
putting a prompt in and they were
getting a bit of lucky and then there
was equally some people that were
suffering that that wasn't working at
all.
>> Yeah. Um but then we found there was
kind of repeatable patterns emerging
around things like um test improvements
or how to make code quality improvements
or reducing complexity of code. Yeah.
And and that was when we started to
experiment with things like unsupervised
agents and you could say okay with this
category of problem um say like we've
got test coverage gaps we want to go and
find all the files that are related to
this part of the codebase related to
this on call say
>> uh find the ones that have got the
biggest coverage gaps and then using
this runbook that we've put together go
and go and cover them go and produce
diffs that help us to
>> bridge the gap
>> and that was the sort of thing that we
lots of hours of manual work and
>> as this sort of evolved we found
actually we can go and use the tools to
go and query the data to find make do
the analysis and then generate the tasks
for itself to go and then fix the tests
and add the coverage uh and I think the
end result was something like 93 and a
half% coverage was achieved which when
we were way less than 60% to start off
with so
>> um many diffs landed
>> and it sounds like like you know huge
productivity gains
>> you introduced a really interesting um
framework called ripper er or riper
back
>> ripper 5. Yeah. Um why don't you
introduce that to to the audience and
then we can kind of like delve deeper
into
>> it. It's first to be fair. I did come up
with it. It was uh we discovered it on a
blog post or a cursor forum that was in
I think March of of this year or so when
we first ran across it. But what it
stands for um it's really it stands for
research, innovate u plan, execute and
then review. So, it's that plan execute
model, but it goes a little bit deeper.
>> And the reason why I think it's so
important is you've been interacting
with an LM, you've been in a chat
console and you're trying to do
something and
>> you it has to have the context of what
you're doing. You don't always are in
the same mindset. You may be trying to
research a particular thing, but it
jumps into coding or you may be planning
and it jump it jumps into coding or
you're coding and it's it's not really
doing any planning. So what the ripper 5
model does is it provides a set of
instructions that um you can pass as a
command. We're using cursor. So we pass
it as kind of um property for our our
our um our our IDE to be able to have
this context. So we give it a command.
We say we're in research mode. And what
that does is it it tells the LLM that
asks me questions, analyze the codebase
of where you're at, for example. Um, but
don't do is as important as what it can
do as is what it can't do. Don't do
coding. Don't do planning. Right now, I
just want you to understand what the
code is, what my what my spec is
actually trying to do, so that way I can
provide more details to refine the spec.
So, this ripper 5, it's kind of like an
execution model of how you work with the
LLM and we do that in pairing with the
with the developer.
>> Why is context so important? Yeah, I
think you kind of got to treat your AI
like a basic junior engineer. If you
don't give him the full requirements of
the task, he's not going to be able to
figure it out, right? So, we need to
make sure all the details that the AI
needs to know, we're providing it.
>> And I think
>> one really good way to do that as well
is with MCPS and setting up some sort of
documentation MCP because there's often
time a lot of gaps in our code where the
AI will read through your code but still
not understand what's going on. But when
we give it access to our documentation,
it can read that and fill in those gaps
which really really boosts the
productivity of what you can produce.
>> Yeah. Amazing. And actually in the
session I asked one of the questions
which was about how you know how to know
when to give you know enough context
without giving so much context that it
actually degrades the performance. Um
and I guess that's what a lot of the
things like when we talk about cursor
rules and the always apply and the apply
manually. It's for exactly that reason.
And I suspect when we look at if if you
wanted if you had a huge amount of
context that you wanted to provide, you
were probably more likely to say
actually there's too much context here.
Let's add this either manually or add it
more intelligently. Apply intelligently
so that way you're not actually bloating
context for no reason. Yeah. Yeah. Super
interesting and actually a really really
crucial part. Um okay, one more curse
rule and we'll jump into uh Claude.
>> Yeah. Yeah. Let's do it. You can have a
bunch of different rules. I think one
that's particularly interesting, Claude
shared this themselves, is relating to
this context we just talked about. Often
times if you get close to the end of
your context window, so you've used up
like 90%. Then you ask the AI for
something, it will give you a short
answer because it's just trying to get
something out before it runs out of
context. But if you type in a prompt
like this or something similar, you can
tell it, hey,
>> your your context is going to end, but
like don't worry about that. You can
compact it. Actually give me the best
answer. And that's one useful tip. What
would happen if you just said to an
agent, you know, here's my environment.
I need you to migrate this, create a
plan and do it yourself,
>> right? What what what would be the
problems?
>> So for a product like this, when you
have hundreds of metrics and each of
them are underpinned with a bunch of
code written in C, you know, with all
the issues I mentioned before about not
all the context necessarily being
exactly where you need it, there's a lot
of complexity in that. You can't just
open up even the state-of-the-art coding
tools like cursor and say hey please
like migrate all of our metrics into you
know into this new abstraction on this
new framework and by the way convert
from C into writing SQL with a YAML for
metric flow on top you it doesn't uh it
doesn't work to do that is what we found
>> um in order to get traction there you
have to really break down
>> the you know break down the mountain of
that problem into small pieces it sounds
kind Obvious if you say in this way you
break it down into standardized into you
break it down into basically a bunch of
similar tasks that can be uh verified in
a standardized way.
>> Yes.
>> And then you assign a long you you
basically construct a long task list
with fa with with phases for individual
sections of the task like move these
first five metrics is you know the first
phase and then the next and
>> and who's doing this? Is this is this
humans doing this? Is this humans with
agents as an assistant? Right. So humans
are you know choosing the the task list
right like are enumerating okay these
are all of the metrics that we're going
to enumerate that we're going to migrate
in phase one and these are the metrics
that we're going to migrate in phase two
so humans are making those choices as
well as like what the target
architecture is that we're going to be
putting these things into and humans are
also you know with some help from like
AI tools are constructing the you know
all of the context that's going to go to
the coding agents to actually enable
them to do the migration work for those
pieces H.